It's such a crucial skill being able to create space between us and our emotion,
so we can respond with the level of values and intentionality.
And yet the language that we have around our emotions can actually keep us stuck.
Often when we are feeling sad, we'll say something like,
I am, I am sad or I am stressed or I am angry.
And when you say, I am, it's almost as if the sadness is a cloud
and you have become the cloud. I am the cloud.
All of me is sad. All of me is angry.
What you can do instead is you can start noticing the thought or the feeling for what it is.
I'm noticing that I'm feeling sad.
I'm noticing that I'm feeling angry.
Because ultimately when you notice that you're having thoughts and feelings,
you create this critical space between you and the emotion
and in it you are able to insert those values, that wisdom.
And this is important because we, after all, are not the cloud.
We are big enough and beautiful enough and messy enough to experience all of our emotions
and still move forward with purpose.
You are not the cloud. You are the whole damn sky.